-= CHD字幕组 原创翻译 =-
字幕仅供翻译学习交流 谢绝用于任何商业用途
翻译：眷念
校对：dahongying
圣杯神器：骸骨之城
嗯，我知道
Yeah, no, I know,
可是我正要按你说的去做的
but when you tell me to do something, I'm gonna do it,
我马上给他发邮件
so I'm e-mailing him right now.
嗯，我不知道他什么时候回复
Well, I don't know how quick he's gonna get back
有时他并不查看邮箱，所以…
'cause you know sometimes he doesn't check, so...
好，诗朗诵会结束
Yeah, and after the poetry reading,
我不回家
I'm not going home.
我是说，今天我生日
I mean, it's my birthday,
我想去夜总会
so I want to go to a club.
不，西蒙，我不想对她撒谎
No, Simon, I'm not gonna lie to her.
我不告诉她就行了呀
I'm just not gonna tell her.
我来停车
Let me go park the truck.
- 等会见，好吗？  - 好
- See you later, all right? - Okay.
喂，多萝西，你好吗？
Hi, Dorothea, how are you?
好吧，我很好，谢了
I'm good, thanks for asking.
我去打电话，多要张门票
So I'll just call, I guess, and get extra tickets.
好，就这样
Yeah, sure.
- 我马上做  - 你好
- I'll do it right now. - Hey, you.
是西蒙
Simon.
是的
Yeah.
你好，西蒙
Hi, Simon.
他说：“会打电话给我”
He says, "Call me."
是啊，是啊，我妈回来了
Yeah, yeah, she just got home.
她肯定听得到，她就站在这儿
I'm sure she can hear you, she's standing right here.
- 你好，卢克  - 你好，克拉蕾
- Hey, Luke. - How's it going, Clary?
没，我马上换衣服
No, I'll get dressed quick.
要咖啡吗？
Do you want some coffee?
你再讲我就得迟到了
If we keep talking, I'm gonna be late.
就那儿见，拜拜
Yeah, I'll meet you there. Bye.
你是不是用了…
Did you just use the...
你觉得呢？
How are you feeling?
好吧，为什么？
Fine, why?
记得晚上直接回来
You make sure you come straight home tonight.
拜托，妈妈 只是个诗歌朗诵会
Mom, come on. Just a poetry reading.
我懂的
I know.
拜拜
Bye.
乔丝琳，你需要跟她谈谈
You need to talk to her, Jocelyn.
不行，她还没准备好
She's not ready, not yet.
不，她准备好了
Yes, she is.
没好的是你
You're not.
另外，谢谢你能来
By the way, thanks for doing this.
他很在意诗朗诵会
His poetry means a lot to him.
谁叫我们是朋友
That's what friends are for.
“来…”
"Come
“难以抗拒的力量…”
"MY faux juggernaut
“我邪恶的下体…”
"My nefarious loins
“涂抹…”
"Slather
“用炽热涂抹每一处隆起吧…”
"Every protuberance with arid zeal
“痛苦…”
"Agony
“折磨”
"Torment"
我听不下去了，要再来杯咖啡吗？
I can't listen to this. You want another coffee?
好
Yeah.
“包裹着的藏红花瓣，低声诉说死亡…”
"Like tiny crocus petals whisper death"
卡布奇诺和浓咖啡
Cappuccino and espresso.
“雨落大地”
"Rain drowns the earth"
“寒风穿过致病的壁毯”
"Shivering breezes weave through a morbid tapestry
“溃烂化脓”
"of festering disease
“我痛苦，全身肿胀”
"Turgid is my torment"
好了
There you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
“雨落大地…”
"Rain drowns the earth..."
刚才那金发女孩蛮喜欢你啊
That blonde girl over there was totally flirting with you.
约她出来
Ask her out.
- 不，那不公平  - 为什么？
- Nah, it wouldn't be fair. - Why?
嗯，因为…
Well, because...
为了某人，我得空着自己
Because I'm saving myself for someone else.
谁？
Who?
“是我的痛”
"Is my torment."
谢谢你，非常感谢
Thank you, thank you very much.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我觉得更不好
Think he's getting worse.
你是他好友，得跟他讲
As his friend, you should probably tell him.
也许他诗歌很棒
Maybe his poetry is great,
我们不懂欣赏吧
we just don't know it yet.
进去看看
Let's go in here.
我想问下这符号的意思
I want to ask what that symbol means.
克拉蕾，我们不该进去
Clary, we'll never get in.
你个担心鬼
Such the eternal optimist.
这可不像你
This is so not like you.
就去这一次啦
Just go with it for once.
这符号代表什么？
What does that symbol mean?
- 什么符号？  - 嗯，哪里有符号？
- What symbol? - Yeah, what symbol?
就在那儿 你没… 你没看见吗？
It's right there. You don't... You don't see it?
没
No.
酷毙了
Hey, that was cool.
嘿，我们进来了
Yeah, we're fitting in.
跟着跳 跟着跳
Move it, go with it.
克拉蕾，要来一杯吗？
Clary, you want a drink?
好
Yeah.
克拉蕾，克拉蕾，那是什么
Clary, Clary, what is it?
你没看到吗？
You didn't see that?
我真的看到
I know what I saw.
让我们进去的那个男孩被杀了
They killed the guy that let us in the club.
- 你是喝迷幻药了？  - 天啦，我没喝，西蒙
- Did you drink something? - Yeah... No, Simon.
你知道，以前我就听说过
You know, I've heard sometimes
有人把迷幻药注射到他们鼻子里
they pump hallucinogenic stuff into the air vents
这样玩会很刺激
to make sure people have a good time.
好了，那你怎会没事？
Okay, then how come you're fine?
我俩呼吸的是不同的空气？
Did we breathe different air?
我不懂，回家好了
I don't know. Let's just go home.
- 你没事吧？  - 没事
- You okay?   - Yeah, fine.
你整整睡了一天
You've been sleeping all day.
而且你昨晚很迟回来
And you didn't come home till late last night.
是的，不过我有回来，对吧？
Yeah, well, I'm home, okay?
不准走
Well, you can't go.
我卖了另一幅画
Well, I sold another painting.
一块去庆祝一下
I wanted to celebrate with you.
庆祝你唯一的买家？
To what, your one buyer?
好吧，他是谁？
Who is this guy anyway?
他买你画估计是爱上你了
He probably just buys your stuff 'cause he's into you.
你肯定像哄卢克那样哄他的吧
I'm sure you'll just string him along like you do with Luke.
你干嘛非得那样说？
You really want to have that conversation?
那什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
- 西蒙  - 他就像我哥
- Simon. - He's like my brother.
我可不认为他这么想
I doubt he feels that way.
好吧，不过我要走了
Okay, well, I'm gonna go.
- 不，不，别走  - 别犯傻了
- No, no, you can't. - This is ridiculous.
- 你去哪里？  - 我只是去加瓦-琼斯咖啡厅
- Where are you going? - I'm just going to Java Jones.
- 我的天！  - 不，是我
- Jesus!     - No, just me.
走吧，西蒙
Come on, Simon.
克拉蕾 我有些事想告诉你，好吗？
Clary. There's something I want to tell you, okay?
以后再说啦
We can talk about this later.
拜拜，弗蕾夫人
Bye, Mrs. Fray.
看，我突然画了很多这些东西
Look, suddenly I'm drawing hundreds of these things,
我不懂怎么搞的
and I have no idea what they are.
我不知道… 我想我快疯了
I don't know. I think I'm going out of my mind.
也许你是《第三类接触中》的那个主角
You know, maybe you're like the guy in Close Encounters.
大家认为他是妄想狂
Everybody thought he was paranoid,
但结果居然是…
and then there turned out to be, well...
幽浮，挺合理的，就像…
UFO, reasonable, like...
哎，天了，这怎么可能发生
Oh, God, this isn't happening.
- 怎么了？  - 这不可能
- What? - This isn't happening.
嘿，现在我被你吓到了
Okay, now you're freaking me out.
克拉蕾，你是…
Clary, are you...
你在看什么？
What are you looking at?
在这等我
Wait here.
乔丝，圣杯在哪？
Where's the Cup, Jocie?
你怎么找到我？
How did you find me?
这得谢你女儿
You can thank your daughter for that.
为何我能看见你而别人不行？
Why can I see you and no one else can?
我还想问你呢？
I was going to ask you the same question.
我怎么会跟你说话
I don't even know why I'm talking to you.
一个杀人狂，一个冷血杀手
You're a killer, a cold-blooded killer.
有这么温和的杀手？
As opposed to a peace-loving killer?
我很明白所看到的
I know what I saw.
你以为你明白
You think you know.
为什么我会画这些？
Why am I drawing this?
我猜对了，你不是凡人
So I was right, you're not a mundane.
等等，凡人？
Excuse me? What's a mundane?
就是人类
Someone from the human world.
我要不是人类，那我是什么？
If I'm not a human, then what am I?
去找圣杯
Go find the Cup.
- 什么时候发生的？  - 不，不
- When did this start? - No, no.
为什么我会画这些？
Why am I drawing this?
回答我！
Answer me!
西蒙
Simon.
你或许得接下，可能是你男友
Maybe you should answer that. Could be your boyfriend.
- 他不是我男友  - 那他知道吗？
- He's not my boyfriend. - Does he know that?
拜托，这很吵
Please. It's annoying.
妈，我要回来了
Mom, I'm coming home.
不，不，不 你不能回家
No, no, no. You can't come home.
听到了吗？别回来
You understand me? You don't come home.
告诉卢克
You call Luke.
说瓦伦丁复活了，他会找到我
Tell him Valentine's alive and that he found me.
我爱你
I love you.
- 妈！ - 不，不！
- Mom!    - No, no!
妈！
Mom!
告诉瓦伦丁他不可能拿到圣杯
You tell Valentine he'll never have the Cup.
别喝… 别喝…
Don't you... Don't drink...
过来！别… 什么？
Come here! Don't... What?
快点！
Come on.
对不起 对不起 你还好吗？
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. You okay?
没事，别动，好吗？
All right, look, don't move, all right?
妈？
Mom?
来，起来
Come on. Come on.
够了！够了！够了！
That's enough! That's enough. That's enough.
它死了
It's dead.
那该死的到底是什么？
What the hell was that?
我说了你肯定不信
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
说说看
Try me.
它是邪灵
It was a demon.
你说得对
You're right.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
而那个东西
And that thing,
你在夜总会看到我杀死的那个…
that you saw me kill at the club, that...
也是一只邪灵
That was also a demon.
邪灵会附身任何活物
Demons can take possession of any living creature.
你谁都不能信
You can't trust anyone.
即使那人你很熟悉
Even people you think you know.
那我干嘛要信你？
So, why should I trust you?
因为我刚才救过你
I did just save your life.
多萝西，快开开门
Dorothea, open up, please.
你能…
Can you...
你知道我妈发生了什么吗？
Do you know what happened to my mom?
你知道吗？
Do you?
等等，你可以看到他？
Wait, you can see this guy?
当然可以 她是女巫
Of course she can. She's a witch.
从姜饼套房降级到了单卧室？
Downgraded from a gingerbread house to a one-bedroom?
你知道我妈在哪里吗？
Do you know where my mom is?
对不起，我不清楚
Sorry. I have no idea.
嗯，她曾提到一个名字… 瓦伦丁
Well, she mentioned a name... Valentine.
- 你最好离开  - 不，请不要这样
- You better leave. - No, please.
你不告诉我，我就不走
Not until you tell me something, anything.
看看骨牌占卜到什么
Let's see what the cards have to say.
对不起，我不信这些…
I'm sorry, but you know that I don't believe in any of...
坐下
Sit.
把手在牌上过一遍
Run your hands over the cards.
我妈妈画过这些
My mom painted these.
是的，你妈妈送的
Yes. They were a gift.
看看你拿到哪一张牌
Let's see which card gets picked.
大金杯
The Ace of Cups.
- 那是圣杯  - 那？
- That's the Mortal Cup. - So?
别理他
Ignore him.
这是圣杯神器
It's a Mortal Instrument,
我们族人三大圣物之一
one of the three holy objects of my people.
它怎么在这儿？
What's it doing here?
我不明白这跟我妈有什么关联
I don't understand what any of this has to do with my mom.
你母亲是暗影猎人，跟他一样
Your mother was a Shadowhunter, like him.
不，我妈是个画家
No, my mom is a painter.
她从没跟你说过，对吧？
She never told you any of this, did she?
我只知道的是她消失了
All I know is that she's gone,
然后我不知道去哪里找她
and I have no idea where to start looking for her.
让我给你读心
Let me read you.
有东西封印了你的回忆
There's something blocking your mind.
我猜是你妈妈雇请了高人来保护你
My guess is your mother hired someone very skilled to protect you.
- 保护什么？  - 你的回忆
- From what? - Your own memories.
为什么？
Why?
我不懂她要我忘记什么
I don't remember anything she'd want me to forget.
等等
Wait.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
搞什么？
What the hell?
你吓到我了
You scared me.
这究竟发生过什么？
What the hell happened here?
- 我妈妈不见了  - 什么？
- My mom's missing. - What?
有人抓了她，还毁了这里
Someone took her and destroyed the place.
他正帮我找她
This guy is helping me find her,
你看不到他，而且他…
but you can't see him, and he...
克拉蕾
Clary.
好吧
Great.
好吧，现在我也看不到他了
Okay, now I can't see him, either.
杰斯·维兰德，邪灵猎手
Jace Wayland, demon hunter.
西蒙·卢易斯，解锁师
Simon Lewis, Keymaster.
你是门卫吗？
Are you the Gatekeeper?
我不懂你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
等等 什么，你现在可以看到他了？
Wait. What, so you can see him now?
- 什么？我当然能看到他  - 可我以为…
- What? Of course I can see him. - But I thought...
- 不…  - 你说什么呢？
- No... - What are you talking about?
我被搞糊涂了
This is so confusing.
这是谁？
Who's this?
我爸爸，我两岁时他就死了
That's my dad. He died when I was two.
克拉蕾，等等
Clary, a moment.
等等，你妈消失了
So, wait, your mom is gone,
你却跟这染金发的追星小伙在一起？
and you're hanging around with some dyed-blond wannabe Goth weirdo?
你在哪儿遇到他的？
Where'd you come across this guy?
- 不，我没有 是他找我的  - 什么？他找你
- No, I didn't. He found me. - What? He found you?
- 不，我知道这听起来…  - 看看这个
- No, I know it sounds... - You should check this.
郑重声明，我头发金色是天生的
And for the record, my hair is naturally blond.
克拉蕾，克拉蕾，克拉蕾… 西蒙？
Clary, Clary, Clary... Simon?
她打过电话？
She called you?
你为什么不接？
Why didn't you pick up?
要是知道这么严重，我早接了
If I'd known it was serious, I would have picked up.
你都没接怎么会知道？
Well, how would you know if you didn't pick it up?
那是什么？
What's that?
没好事
Nothing good.
你懂她哪儿弄来这个的吗？
Do you have any idea where she got this?
我得找卢克
I've got to find Luke.
太奇怪了，他车在这儿
It's so weird. His truck's here.
来吧 这边
Come on. This way.
不，你在这等
No, you wait here.
干嘛要听你的？
Who made you the boss?
没关系，这样有人来能通知我们
It's okay. Just let us know if anyone comes.
我认识卢克好多年
I've known Luke all these years,
但我都没下来过
but I've never been down here.
什么？
What?
快点，伙计！
Come on, mate!
伙计，听好…
Now, listen...
你要做的就是说真话
All you got to do, mate, is tell me the truth.
我说了，不知道圣杯在哪儿
I'm telling you, I don't know where the Cup is.
我知道你和乔丝关系好
I know you and Jocie are close.
我可不是傻子？
I'm not stupid, am I?
别这样回答
Don't answer that.
听我说，伙计
Listen to me, mate.
只要告诉我圣杯在哪儿
Just tell me where the Mortal Cup is.
乔丝就会没事
And then Jocie will be fine.
卢克，说啊，告诉我
Lukey, tell me. Tell me the truth.
我不知道
I don't know.
你可别惹我生气
You don't want to make me angry.
- 我说了…  - 是吗？
- I'm telling you... - Do you?
我再问一遍，伙计
I'm going to ask you again, mate,
圣杯在哪儿？
where's the Cup, huh?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们都需要它，卢克，不是吗？
We all want the same thing, Lukey boy, don't we?
不同之处，我觉得你知道它在哪儿
Difference is, I think you know where it is.
不是吗？
Don't you?
快点 快点 说啊！
Come on. Come on. Talk!
- 我们得走了  - 不，求你了，你要帮他
- We need to go. - No, please, you have to help him.
你不懂
You don't understand.
他们是瓦伦丁的人
They work for Valentine.
他是个死人 我帮不了他
He's a dead man. I can't help him.
他是我家人
He's like family.
奇了怪
You know what's really amazing
你看上去还挺像人类
is how much you actually look like a human.
很棒啊？
Isn't it great?
求你了
Please.
你要发狂了？你要变身了？
Are you gonna get mad? You're going to change?
我要看你变身
I want to see you change.
给我露露你怎么变身的？
Show me how you can change. Huh?
看看 看看
Look at that. Look at that.
狼人来了
Dog boy's coming on.
你想搞我腿？
You want to hump my leg?
你搞我腿？喜欢这样？
You hump legs? You like that?
要嗅我屁股吗？
You want to smell my derriere?
我要看你　变身
I want to see you change!
告诉我乔丝琳把圣杯藏哪儿
You just got to tell me where Jocelyn hid the Cup.
然后你可以平安带回她
Then you can have her back.
她会平安无事的
She'll be safe and sound.
我没要她回来
I don't want her back.
我一点不在乎
I couldn't care less.
我这么多年
I have spent years
一直在讨好她和她的倔女儿，就是为圣杯
cozying up to that woman and her brat for the Mortal Cup.
潘伯恩，听我说
Pangborn, listen to me.
我也想把圣杯给瓦伦丁
I want to be the one to give her to Valentine.
呀，对
Yeah, right.
你在犯大错
You are making a big mistake.
我不信，你信他吗？
I don't believe you. Do you believe him?
- 克拉蕾，快跑！  - 克拉蕾，听我说！
- Clary, run!          - Clary, listen!
劳驾 警官？
Excuse me. Officer?
我要报案，有人闯入
I'd like to report a break-in.
一人失踪
And a missing person.
有人闯入我朋友的家…
My friend's house got broken into, and...
- 她妈妈失踪了  - 哦，不
- Her mom's missing. - Oh, no.
快跑！
Run!
- 你杀了两个警察！  - 他们不是警察
- You killed two cops! - They weren't cops.
快走！
Let's go!
克拉蕾
Clary.
你不能留在这儿 他们会抓到你的
You can't stay here. They'll find you.
卢克怎么会说他不在乎？
How could Luke say that he didn't care?
我从记事起就认识他了
I've known him for as long as I can remember.
他曾每晚都为我读故事
He used to read to me every night.
他天天来校接我好几年了
He's been picking me up at school for years.
也许这记忆不真实
Look, maybe those memories aren't real.
你不记得我说的了吗？
Do you remember what I told you?
谁都不能相信
You can't trust anyone.
不，我要找回妈妈，我要回家
No, I need to find my mom. I have to go home.
- 我肯定漏了什么！  - 听我说，好吗？
- There must be something that I missed! - Listen to me, okay?
我们会弄清的，但不是此时此地
We'll figure this out, but not here and not now.
你得到一个安全的地方
We need to get you to a safe place.
我是暗影猎人，克拉蕾
I'm a Shadowhunter, Clary,
我会誓死保护你
and I will protect you with my life.
你们在这儿，我以为你们紧跟着
There you guys are. I thought you were right behind me.
我丢了你们
I thought I'd lost you.
好吧，我跟着你
Okay. I'll follow you.
你确定吗？他刚杀了两个警察
Are you sure about that? 'Cause he just killed two cops.
呀，他们不是警察
Yeah, they weren't cops.
我觉得他们就是
They looked like real cops to me.
- 他们不是真警察  - 好吧
- They weren't real cops. - Okay.
那他们那儿弄来的警车？
So, where did they get the car?
他们不是真警察
They weren't real cops.
在这我们会很安全
We'll be safe in here.
这鬼地方是哪里？
What is this dump?
这不是鬼地方
This isn't a dump.
只不过你看不见
You just can't see it.
到底怎么了？他们做了什么？
What the hell is going on? What are they doing in here?
- 这是被邪灵咬伤  - 克拉蕾
- It's a demon bite. - Clary.
杰斯，做点什么！
Jace, do something!
接下来是不是你该撕掉你的衬衣
Is this the part when you start tearing off pieces of your shirt
包扎我的伤口呢？
to bind my wounds?
如果你要我把这身衣服脱下来
If you wanted me to take my clothes off,
只要你发话就行
you should've just asked.
只是有点发烧
It's just a fever.
她醒了
She's waking up.
我昏倒后你们给纹的？
I passed out, and you guys tattooed me?
我以为这只在赌城才会发生
Thought that only happened in Vegas.
- 这不是纹身  - 是图符
- It's not a tattoo. - It's a rune.
它让你拥有一切：
They have them for everything,
隐身术，强健之躯和自愈术
they make you invisible, strong, they heal.
它让你可见
They also make you visible.
所以我突然可以看到他
That's why I could suddenly see him.
- 即使你不吃饭…  - 不
- Even if you're hungry... - No.
事实上，这图符是让你可以看到我们
The fact that the rune had an effect on you explains why you can see us.
我没弄懂
I don't get it.
凡人是挺不过来的
Mundanes can't survive the process.
他们无法承受这图符的力量，所以…
The runes are too strong for them, so...
现在，我们很确定你有暗影猎人的血脉
Now we definitely know you have Shadowhunter blood.
等等，那之前就不确定了？
Wait, it wasn't definite before?
她没死，才让我们更确定，是这样的
Well, it became definite when she didn't die. Yes.
看看合不合身
Here, see if these fit.
我们这不是天天有贵客的
It's not every day we get guests in here.
尤其少见女客人
Especially not girls.
是啊
Yeah.
我们要叫警察来吗？
Shouldn't we call the cops?
我指的是真警察
I mean, the real ones.
好主意
That's a great idea.
我只是不懂我们为何没想到过
I just don't know why we haven't thought of that
在过去的这几千年中
for the past thousand years.
霍奇在等她
Hodge is ready for her.
他想在藏书馆单独见她
He wants to see her alone in the library.
霍奇是谁？
Who's Hodge?
他是这里的头
He's in charge of the Institute.
好吧，我们走
Okay, let's go.
无数的暗影猎人曾来此寻求庇护
Hundreds of Shadowhunters used to seek asylum here.
但你也看到了
But, as you can see,
现在只剩我们这几个了
right now, we're the only ones.
没有圣杯，我们只能等死
Without the Mortal Cup, we're a dying breed.
要么你是暗影猎人的后代
Either you're born of a Shadowhunter,
要么你有喝过圣杯之水
or you have to drink from the Mortal Cup.
你来自
You coming?
遥远的布鲁克林，对吧？
Pretty far from Brooklyn, isn't it?
离杰斯远点
Stay away from Jace.
你可能觉得霍奇有点古怪
You may find Hodge a little eccentric,
但他曾是最出色的暗影猎人之一
but he's one of the greatest Shadowhunters that's ever lived.
这给我
Here, give me that.
你不觉得这有点冒险
Don't you think it's a bit risky
让一个完全陌生的人
inviting a complete stranger
闯进神院中心？
into the heart of the Institute?
不，我们可以相信她
No. I think we can trust her.
那她的凡人朋友呢？
And what about her mundane friend?
嗯，这是一时疏忽
Well, that was impulsive.
你一时疏忽，会弄砸事
When you're impulsive, things go badly.
当心
Just be careful,
自愈心碎的图符是最疼的
the rune to fix a broken heart is the most painful one.
我保证适时让他们离开
They'll be out of here in a day, I promise.
杰斯
Jace.
她曾是最出色的猎人之一
She was one of the best,
你的母亲
your mum.
但我不明白为什么她…
But I don't understand why...
昨天你还只是个普通的女孩
Yesterday you were just a normal girl.
今天仿佛感觉到
Today you feel as though
你的世界彻底翻天覆地改变了
your whole world has been turned upside down.
你必须知道一件事
There's only one thing you need to know.
那是你小时候听到的故事
The stories you were told as a little girl
怪兽和梦魇
about monsters, nightmares,
篝火旁低诉的传说…
legends whispered around campfires...
他们都是真的
They're all true.
- 邪灵？  - 对
- Demon?    - Yes.
邪灵？
Demon?
不，狼人不是邪灵
No. Werewolves aren't demons.
我们和地下生物有过停战协议
We have a truce with Downworlders.
地下生物？
Downworlders?
是什么？14号街以下的人？
What is that, like people below 14th Street?
嗯，“地下生物”包括很多
Well, "Downworlders" pretty much sums everything up,
吸血鬼，狼人和术士
vampires, werewolves, Warlocks.
术士，很酷啊
Warlocks. Cool.
你怎么杀死一只僵尸的？
So, how do you kill a zombie?
我们没杀
We don't.
当然他们已经死了
Of course, they're already dead.
不，他们不存在
No. They don't exist.
那么这就是大家所说的圣杯吧
So, that's the famous Cup everyone's talking about.
只是个模型，不过也对
A replica. But yes.
那你知道杰斯敏感易怒咯
You know, Jace has got a real chip on his shoulder.
你也一样的
You would, too,
如果你小时候亲眼看到你父亲被杀
if you saw your father murdered when you were a child.
要不是他，我们全死了
If it weren't for him, we'd be dead.
我都说不清他救了我们多少次了
He saved our lives more times than I care to admit.
好吧
Right.
据传说
The legend goes,
十字军曾召唤过一位天使
the Crusaders summoned an angel,
天使拉齐尔
the Angel Raziel.
拉齐尔将自己的鲜血倒入圣杯
Raziel poured his blood into a cup,
那些喝过其血的人
and those who drank from it
变成半天使，半凡人
became half angel, half human.
暗影猎人
Shadowhunters.
这会遗传给他们的子子孙孙
As did their children and their children's children.
有强大力量的族群
Beings of immense power,
足以恢复和平
strong enough to restore balance
保护世界，抵御邪灵
and protect the world in a war against evil.
这是无赢家的斗争
A war that can never be won,
但永无休止
but must always be fought.
因为邪灵永生不息
Demons don't die easily.
但我们却终有一死
Whereas we, we remained all too mortal.
你们干嘛不用圣杯
Why didn't they just use the Cup
繁衍出更多的暗影猎人？
to create more Shadowhunters?
瓦伦丁也这么说过
Valentine's exact words.
克拉夫－圣杯守护者
The Clave, the keepers of the Cup,
他们害怕其力量
they were afraid of using its power.
他们知道没人能承受住圣杯的力量而存活
They knew that hardly anyone who drank from it survived.
瓦伦丁·摩根斯坦召集了一群朋友
Valentine Morgenstern drew a circle of friends together,
一群年轻妄想的暗影猎人
young, idealistic Shadowhunters,
帮他从克拉夫手里偷到了圣杯
to help him steal the Mortal Cup from the Clave.
但瓦伦丁并不想保护人类
But he didn't want to protect humanity.
他相信暗影猎人可以进化
He believed there had to be an evolution of Shadowhunters,
变得更具力量
something more powerful.
他开始试着使用圣杯
He began experimenting, using the Mortal Cup.
并学会了召唤邪灵
He learned how to summon demons.
他甚至给自己注射过邪灵的鲜血
He even injected himself with demon blood
以此来控制他们
so he could control them.
他想统治一切
He wanted to rule.
为了阻止他，你妈妈
Your mother, to prevent that,
偷走了圣杯
stole the Cup from him,
而后消失不见
and vanished into thin air.
但要是只有她知道圣杯在哪里，那么…
But if she's the only one that knows where the Cup is, then...
也许不只她
Maybe she isn't.
她可能告诉某人了
Maybe she told someone else.
一个没有人猜到她知道的人
Someone who doesn't know she knows.
赛任兄弟们在等她
The Silent Brothers are ready for her.
为什么霍奇不一块来？
Why didn't Hodge come with us?
他好多年没离开神院了
He hasn't left the Institute in years.
有人说是诅咒
Some say it's a spell.
他有恐旷症吧
He's agoraphobic.
是他吗？
Is that him?
不，那是哈罗德，扫地工
No, that's Harold, the groundskeeper.
是他
That's him.
你想好要经历这些了吗？
Are you sure you want to go through with this?
我们会帮你解开回忆
We will help you to remember.
你会吵醒亡灵的
You'll wake the dead.
难以置信，这地方就在城市外
I can't believe this place is just outside the city.
欢迎来到　骸骨之城
Welcome to the City of Bones.
这是赛任兄弟汲取力量的源泉
This is where the Silent Brothers draw their power,
暗影猎人的骸骨和骨灰
from the bones and ashes of Shadowhunters.
他们都埋在这里？
All of them are buried here?
对，有一天
Yes. One day,
我会在这里
that's gonna be me.
我只能跟到这儿了
This is as far as I go.
你不会有事的
You'll be fine.
你之前试过吗？
So you've done this before?
没
No.
你必须倾听自己的内心
You must listen with your mind.
妈？
Mom?
去，去
Go. Go.
克拉蕾，这是卢克
Clary, this is Luke,
我最好的朋友
my dearest friend.
你可以信任他
You can trust him.
你好，克拉蕾
Hi, Clary.
别说
Don't tell.
别碰那老东西
Don't touch that old thing.
只是个旧杯子，克拉蕾
It's just an old cup, Clary.
克拉蕾！克拉蕾，你还好吗？
Clary! Clary, are you okay?
克拉蕾？
Clary?
封印比预想的要强
Your block is stronger than I anticipated.
解铃还须系铃人了
It can only be undone by the one who put it there.
我不清楚系铃人是谁
I have no idea who put it there.
你写出来了
You wrote it.
你记得是相反的印象
Your mind remembers the inverted image.
要换个角度看
Just have to look at it differently.
“贝恩”
"B-A-N-E."
- 贝恩  - 是谁？
- Bane.    - Who?
马格努斯·贝恩，我记得他是个术士
Magnus Bane. He's a warlock. I should have known.
好，那找他去
Well, let's go talk to him then.
不能这样去
Not like that.
你需要伊莎贝尔的协助
We're gonna need some help from Isabelle.
这是上衣
This is a top.
是连衣裙
It's a dress.
我穿不了
I can't pull this off.
就差双合适的鞋子…
Well, actually, with the right shoes...
不，我是说…
No, I mean...
这衣服太紧，像包了一层皮一样
This dress is so tight, it's like a second skin.
你难道没有别的了吗？
Don't you have anything else?
要是你穿得像凡人那样去的话
If you go out looking like your mundane self,
我们接近不了马格努斯·贝恩
we won't get within a hundred feet of Magnus Bane.
他是布鲁克林的高级术士
He's the High Warlock of Brooklyn.
别抱怨了，过来
Now, stop complaining, come over here.
拿着
Hold this.
亚力克好像很讨厌我
That guy Alec doesn't like me very much.
亚力克是我的兄弟
That guy Alec is my brother.
杰斯知道亚力克对他的感觉吗？
Does Jace know how Alec feels about him?
很明显吗？
Is it that obvious?
这真没什么大不了的
It's really not that big of a deal.
对我也一样
It isn't to me either.
但对克拉夫不同
But it is to the Clave.
规则不是我定的
I don't make the rules.
看，现在多漂亮
See? You look pretty.
干嘛要穿得这么妖艳
How is being dressed like a hooker
会帮我找到妈妈？
gonna help me find my mom?
放松点，那些只是我的衣服而已
Easy now, those are my clothes.
亚力克，她看上去漂亮吧？
Doesn't she look great, Alec?
她看上去就像
She looks like someone
留电话号码在浴室墙上的人
whose phone number should be on a bathroom wall.
我觉得你很漂亮
I think you look great.
等等，我来过这里
Wait, I've been here.
- 等等  - 怎么了？
- Wait.     - What?
这样更好点？
Is that better?
更好了
It's better.
嘿，嘿，嘿
Well, well, well.
瞧瞧这儿
Look-a here.
什么风把人神的孩子们吹到这儿
I don't remember inviting any children of the Nephilim.
马格努斯·贝恩，我们要谈谈
Magnus Bane. We need to talk.
我不喜欢你们
You know I don't like you guys.
但我还让你们待在这儿
But I'll let you stay,
只是因为这火辣宝贝
but only because of the hot one.
- 谢谢  - 谢谢
- Thanks. - Thank you.
什么？
What?
我说的是他
I meant him.
蓝眼睛的那位
The one with the blue eyes.
还有克拉蕾
And because of Clary.
等等，你怎么知道她名字？
Wait. How do you know her name?
跟我来
Come with me.
- 你妈妈呢？  - 她失踪了
- Where's your mother? - She's missing.
原来如此
That explains it.
她每年都带你来这儿
Every year, she brought you here.
从来没有漏过一次
She never missed an appointment.
我在你身上下的咒语是最成功的
Not every spell turns out as perfect as the one I did on you.
一旦你开始画天使图符
As soon as you started drawing the angelic rune,
说明你的记忆又回来了
it was a sign your memory was surfacing.
我将此咒深藏在你记忆中
I had built that into your mind
她就能适时带你回来封印
so that she knew when to bring you back.
暗影世界里的一切，你都会忘记
What you saw from the shadow world,
即使你看过
you would forget, even as you saw it.
可你越长大
But as you grew older,
你需要封印的次数也越来越多
you needed my treatment more frequently.
她知道有一天非得告诉你
She knew she had to tell you one day,
但想等你准备好后
but until you were ready,
她想封印回忆
she wanted to keep the block on your mind.
这就是她想做的
It was exactly how she wanted it.
我们要在这儿待多久？
How long do you think we're gonna be here?
西蒙，放松点，好吗？
Relax, Simon, okay?
别喝！
Don't drink that!
西蒙！西蒙！
Simon! Simon!
时间会消磨封印
It'll wear off over time.
现在已经磨去了，要么你不会来这儿
It's already wearing off, or you wouldn't be here.
我还是记不起来
I need to remember.
我妈没有多少时间了
My mom doesn't have time.
求你了，你肯定能做点什么
Please, there must be something you can do.
你就是买我母亲画的人
You're the one who's been buying all my mom's paintings.
你为什么每幅都买？
Why did you buy all of them?
我清楚她需要钱
I knew she needed the money.
你甚至有我爸爸的画像
You even have a portrait of my dad.
那不是你爸
That's not your dad.
他只是战死在伊朗的一名士兵
He's a soldier who died in Iraq.
乔丝琳从没见过他
Jocelyn never even met the guy.
有人请她画的
She was asked to paint his portrait,
但这对一位寡妇来说太痛苦了
but it was too painful for the widow.
她保留着画，所以…
She kept the picture so...
她就能假装他是我爸爸
She could pretend he was my dad.
她做的一切都是为了你
Everything she did, she did for you.
你妈妈生命中的一切：
Your mother's whole existence,
逃跑，躲藏，谎言
the running, the hiding, the lies,
都是为了你的安全
were to keep you safe.
她有跟我说过什么真话吗？
Was anything she ever told me true?
你头脑里藏着一幅宝藏图，克拉蕾
There's a treasure map inside your head, Clary.
找到圣杯，它能带你找到你妈妈
Find the Cup, and it will lead you to your mother.
他们把西蒙带走了
They've taken Simon.
- 谁？  - 吸血鬼
- Who?   - Vampires.
别忘了
Just remember,
你妈妈躲避的正是暗影猎人
it was Shadowhunters your mother was running from.
我们去找西蒙
Let's go find Simon.
我们不能闯进吸血鬼的老巢，我们从没试过
We can't break into a vampire's lair, we never learned.
- 又开始了你  - 杰斯，这你知道的
- Don't start again. - Jace, you know the rules.
伙计，我们来这干嘛？
Guys, what are we doing here?
我们不是要找西蒙吗？
I thought we were trying to find Simon.
我们知道他在哪，只是需要先拿些东西
We know where he is. We just need to pick up a few things.
这是什么？你们和教堂有某种约定？
What is this, some kind of deal you have with the church?
邪灵在世界各地都有
Demons exist all across the world
而且外形各异
in their varying, different forms.
暗影猎人从不单信某个宗教
Shadowhunters cling to no particular religion,
因此，所有宗教都能协助我们作战
and in turn all religions assist us in our battle.
我们自如穿梭在犹太教堂
We could have as easily gone to a Jewish synagogue
或神道教塔…
or a Shinto temple or...
在这
Here it is.
在每个教堂的祭坛底下…
Beneath every altar in every church...
都能找到这个
you'll find this.
那你们信仰什么？
So, what do you believe in?
我信仰自己
I believe in myself.
我知道杀死邪灵是我的职责
I know my job is to kill demons.
其它我一概不信
I don't have to believe in anything else.
那天使拉齐尔呢？
What about the Angel Raziel?
那是美丽的传说
Yeah, makes for a nice story.
- 但霍奇说…  - 是啊，霍奇
- But Hodge thinks... - Yeah, Hodge.
他还有很多没说
He needs to get out more.
- 我原以为…  - 听着，我一直在猎杀邪灵
- I thought... - Listen, I've been hunting demons
已经花掉了我三分之一的生命
for over a third of my life,
到目前为止，从未见过天使
and in all that time, I've never seen an angel.
这儿
Here.
这，你拿这个
Here, you take this one.
我不会…
I don't...
这，我教你
Here, let me show you.
这是一把杀吸血鬼的枪，必须瞄准他们的心脏
It's a vampire gun. Must pierce the heart.
推上来，对着胸膛
Push it up against the chest.
开火
Fire.
再装枪 重发
Recharge. Then you're good to go again.
死人客栈？
Hotel of Death?
他们也有幽默感
You can't say they don't have a sense of humor.
快点
Come on.
- 她怎么办？  - 她很勇敢
- What is it about her? - She's brave.
我们暗影猎人都勇敢
We're Shadowhunters, we're all brave.
她不像我们那样抚养长大，她不同
She wasn't raised like us, she's different.
她会连累我们被杀
She's gonna get us all killed.
是西蒙的衬衫
Simon's shirt.
他在上面
He's up here.
西蒙
Simon.
- 我的天，我的天，西蒙  - 克拉蕾
- Oh, my God, oh, my God, Simon. - Clary.
不，我能触到他了！
No, I can feel him!
搭把手 快点，快点
Give me a hand. Come on, come on.
这该死的靴子！
These damn boots!
这儿
Here.
好
Here you go.
- 快点  - 伙计，稳住
- Come on. - Guys, steady.
慢点
Slowly.
他还活着！
He's alive!
小心
Careful.
快走，他们要的不是我
Go on. Get out. They don't want me.
要的是你，他们要的是圣杯
They want you, they want the Cup.
- 快点，走  - 天啊
- Come on. Let's go. - Oh, God.
快！
Let's go!
不，这儿
No, here.
- 这儿！  - 走！
- In here! - Go!
杰斯
Jace.
你身后！
Behind you!
快点！快点！
Come on! Come on!
克拉蕾！
Clary!
他们人数太多
There's too many of them.
抱点信念
Have a little faith.
跑！
Run!
杰斯，给我把短刀
Jace, I need a knife.
- 日出  - 快走
- The sun. - Let's go.
帮西蒙
You help Simon.
克拉蕾！
Clary!
抓住！
Hold on!
克拉蕾！
Clary!
谢谢
Thank you.
你救了西蒙
For saving Simon.
- 还好吗？  - 我没事，我没事
- Are you okay? - I'm okay, I'm okay.
克拉蕾
Clary.
能和你谈谈吗？
Can I talk to you?
行，我正要去看西蒙
Yeah, I was just gonna go see Simon.
- 我希望你离开这儿  - 什么？
- I want you to leave here. - What?
你差点让我们送死
You almost got us killed.
对不起，我们别无选择
I'm sorry, we didn't have a choice.
要救西蒙，而杰斯…
I mean, we had to save Simon, and Jace...
杰斯应该拯救世界
Jace thinks he needs to save the world.
但你没鼓励他这么做
But you don't need to encourage him to do it.
这就是你们要做的
But that's what you guys do.
对，我们　要做的
Yes, us. What we do.
我们是团队，你是累赘
We're a team, you're deadweight.
- 凡人  - 我不是凡人
- A mundane. - I'm not a mundane.
你要是表现得有半点勇敢
And if you were half as brave as you pretend to be,
就得承认…
you'd admit that...
什么？
What?
你承认你爱上了杰斯
You'd admit that you're in love with Jace,
这才是千真万确的
and that's what this is really about.
你敢再这样说一下…
If you ever say anything like that again...
我定杀死你
I'll kill you.
- 我晕了多久？  - 一整天
- How long was I out? - All day.
你的眼镜
Found your glasses.
- 有一边镜片裂了  - 嗯
- One of the lenses cracked. - Yeah.
好神奇
How weird.
我似乎不需要它了
I don't seem to need them anymore.
那你在画什么？
So, what are you drawing?
没什么
Nothing.
- 你还好吗？  - 还好
- You okay?     - Yeah.
这太疯狂了
It was crazy.
对不起之前我不相信你
I'm sorry I didn't believe you before.
现在我信了
Now I get it.
还有…
And...
当时我昏倒了
And I must have passed out,
接着你就出现
and then you showed up.
听着
Listen,
我知道我总是那个要被依赖的人
I know I've always been the one who needed you
比起你依赖我来
more than you needed me.
- 不是真的  - 是真的
- That's not true. - Yes, it is,
但我不在乎
but I never cared.
我只有妈妈，卢克和你了
I've only ever had my mom, Luke and you.
别乱想你对我来说不重要
Don't ever imagine that you weren't important to me.
- 好吧  - 好吧
- Okay.   - Okay.
你跟钢琴有仇吗？
What did that piano ever do to you?
好像失去唯一真爱一样
You play it like you've lost your only love.
不幸的是我唯一真爱就是自己
Unfortunately, my one true love remains myself.
至少你不用愁遭拒绝
Well, at least you don't have to worry about rejection.
那也不一定
Not necessarily.
我有时会自我分裂，寻求刺激
I turn myself down occasionally just to keep it interesting.
你弹得很有热情
You do play that with a lot of passion.
这才有问题
Well, that's the problem.
我不该投入太多感情
I play it with too much emotion.
本应该只是简单地音符重现
It's supposed to be played with a simple representation of notes,
而不是诠释
no interpretation.
音乐就该有感情
Music is supposed to have emotion.
邪灵对交错的音调才有反应
Demons react to certain frequencies when two tones cross.
才能使他们癫狂
Drives them crazy.
看，巴赫发现这点并构建了一个体系
See, Bach discovered this and put it into a system using
用数字序列融合音调
a mathematical progression of tonal combinations
可以显现邪灵
that allows us to expose demons.
那巴赫也是个暗影猎人咯？
So Bach was a Shadowhunter?
- 是的  - 这么说…
- Yes.        - So...
巴赫对于邪灵们就像大蒜对于吸血鬼
Bach is to demons what garlic is to vampires.
也对吧
Kind of.
我是说：大蒜会被用尽
I mean, you can run out of garlic.
但音乐却无止境
You can't really run out of music.
那里放着你的玩意吗？
Is that where you keep all your toys?
有趣得多
It's way more fun.
来吧
Come on.
这是穿梭门
It's a portal.
像百慕大一样的自然现象
Like the Bermuda Triangle, it's a natural phenomenon.
神院围绕它而建
The Institute was built around it.
据说神院是纽约最早的建筑
Some say that the Institute was the first building in New York.
所以它…
So it's...
空间不都只是直线型的
Dimensions aren't all just straight lines.
也会有弯曲
There's bends,
折叠，凹角
folds and nooks.
有点难以解释，不过
It's a little bit difficult to explain, but
穿梭门能带你到任何你想去的地方
the Portal can take you wherever you want to go in this dimension.
一旦穿过表面
So, as soon as you break that surface,
你就会被送到你心底最深处
you're transported to wherever your deepest thoughts lie.
那意味着…
So that means...
- 我妈妈…  - 等下
- My mom... - Wait.
我们训练一生才懂得使用它
We spend our entire lives training how to use it,
进入前要先想象一下所去之处
visualizing where it will take us before we step into it,
那必须要非常集中精力
and that takes incredible focus.
如果没有经过正确训练而进入的话
If you were to step into it without the proper training,
你将永无安定
you could end up in limbo,
永生困在记忆之中
lost in your own mind forever.
这儿
Here.
我做给你看
Let me show you.
快点
Come on.
别偷看
No peeking.
很酷吧，对吧？
Pretty cool, isn't it?
现在…
Now...
你和我…
You and I...
要庆祝你的生日
Have a birthday to celebrate.
你怎么知道？
How did you know?
我之前找你，就查到过
Research. When I was trying to find you.
不会有人来这儿
No one comes up here anymore.
这里属于我们
We have the place to ourselves.
美得窒息了
This is breathtaking.
抱歉，没有蛋糕
Sorry there's no cake.
我原本就没期望
Well, I was expecting nothing,
这已很棒了
so this is great.
不过，每个人都该在生日那天得到些什么
Well, everyone should get something for their birthday.
你生日得到什么？
What did you get?
大多数是武器
Weapons mostly.
希望没让你吃惊
I'm sure that doesn't surprise you.
现在没有什么会让我吃惊
At this point, nothing really does.
当我九岁时…
When I was nine...
我父亲送了我一只隼
My father gave me a falcon.
他要我让它听话
He told me to make it obedient.
我本该弄瞎那只鸟
I was supposed to keep the bird blind,
但我做不到
but I couldn't bring myself to do it.
相反的是，我抚摸它的翅膀
Instead, I touched and stroked its wings
直到它信任我
until it trusted me.
我以为完美地驯服了它
I tamed it to perfection.
我把它带给父亲
I took it to my father,
希望父亲为我所做的感到骄傲
expecting him to be proud of what I'd done.
他说：
He said,
“我是要你让他听话”
"I told you to make it obedient.
“不是要你教它爱你”
"Instead, you taught it to love you.
“你没有驯服它，你毁了它”
"You didn't tame it, you broke it."
他带走鸟，并割了它的脖子
Then he took the bird and he broke its neck.
我当时哭了整整一夜，此后再没哭过
I cried all night and I never cried again.
你原谅他吗？
Did you ever forgive him?
他这么做是要我强大
He did it to make me stronger.
那是你名字维兰德的意义吗？
Does that stand for Wayland?
午夜
Midnight.
瞧瞧这些
Watch this.
一个女孩说要一颗大宝石
When a girl says she wants a big rock,
但她并非就是这个意思
she doesn't literally mean a big rock.
每个暗影猎人都有属于自己的魔石
Every Shadowhunter should have their own witchlight.
有人在
We have company.
那只是霍奇的鸟
That's Hodge's bird.
我们得走了
We should probably go.
是啊
Yeah.
我们真得走了
We should definitely go.
抱歉忘记告诉你会定时喷水
Sorry about the sprinkler system.
别提它了
I forgot about that.
要去睡了吗？
You going to sleep?
累了吗？
Well, aren't you tired?
我从没这样清醒
I've never been more awake.
- 西蒙，我以为你…  - 睡了？
- Simon, I thought you were... - Asleep?
之前是的
Yeah, I was.
我们只不过…
We were just...
下次，最好是
Next time, it might be a nice idea
你得说你已经有个男人在床上
to mention that you already have a man in your bed,
我们才不会这么尴尬了
so we can avoid such uncomfortable situations.
你让他到你床上？
You invited him to bed?
我知道这挺荒唐的，是不是？
I know, it's ridiculous, isn't it?
不可能一切合心意
We would never have all fit.
我没有让他到我床上
I didn't invite him into bed.
只是接吻而已
We were just kissing.
你太快丢掉我俩的爱了
How swiftly you dismiss our love.
杰斯…
Jace...
西蒙，很晚了，对不起吵醒你
Simon, it's late, and I'm sorry we woke you.
我也是
So am I.
去吧，去找他，去向他道歉
Go ahead. Go after him, go apologize to him,
去跟他说他才是特别的
go tell him just how special he really is.
- 别这样！  - 哪样了？
- Stop acting like that! - Like what?
好像你没受伤一样
Like nothing ever hurts you.
嗯，也许你应该想清楚的
Well, maybe you should have thought about that
在你亲我之前
before you kissed me.
是我亲你？
I kissed you?
别担心，这对我也没什么了不起
Don't worry, it wasn't that special for me either.
西蒙，真的很抱歉，我还以为你在…
I'm really sorry, Simon, but weren't you just in the...
我只是在找你
I was just looking for you.
- 你要去哪儿？  - 回家
- Where are you going? - Home.
显然我在这太久，不受欢迎了
It's clear I overstayed my welcome.
对不起，这对我也太突然了
Look, I'm sorry, okay? It wasn't like it was planned.
但就是发生了，拜托
Let me guess, it just happened. Please.
听着，我知道你不喜欢他，但是…
Look, I know you don't like him, but...
其实我恨他
Actually, I hate the guy.
为什么？
Why?
我以为你不至于爱上他
I thought you were better than that.
那这又说明什么？
What's that supposed to mean?
我才是一直等你的人，不是他
I'm the one who's always been there for you, not him.
我早爱上你了
I'm in love with you.
不过显然你没有同感
And it's clear that you don't feel the same way.
- 这…  - 不
- It's... - Don't.
没什么好说了
There's nothing to say.
还有，克拉蕾
And, Clary,
他只是利用你获得圣杯
he's just using you to get the Cup.
西蒙…
Simon...
你母亲也能这么做
Your mother was the only other person who could do that.
但我之前从没这么做过
But I've never been able to do this before.
说明封印住的不仅是你的回忆
Apparently the block wasn't just repressing your memories,
还有你的能力
but your abilities as well.
- 杰斯，我…  - 别跟我说
- Jace, I... - Don't tell me.
你急需一个裸模来画画
You have a drawing emergency and you need a nude model.
- 没那个心情  - 听着！
- I'm not in the mood. - Listen!
我知道我妈妈将圣杯藏哪儿了
I know where my mom hid the Cup.
克拉蕾…
Clary...
你看上去很不同
Wow, you look different.
嗯，这只是我借来的
Yeah, it's just something I borrowed.
我是说，你穿得很漂亮
I mean, nice outfit. It's good.
好吧，现在我没空聊 抱歉
Yeah, I can't talk now. Sorry.
（西蒙，克拉蕾刚进她家）
- 克拉蕾  - 我来拿塔罗牌
- Clary. - I came for the tarot cards.
- 为什么？  - 我需要他们
- Why?          - I need them.
你懂的，就是我妈妈画的那些？
You know, the ones that Mom painted?
我就想快点看看
I just need to look at them really quickly,
然后就还你，我发誓
and I'll give them back, I promise.
武器别带进来
Those can't come in here.
这是和平之地
This is a peaceful house.
放那儿
Put them in there.
今天感觉怎么样？
How are you feeling today?
很好，很好
Fine. Just fine.
小伙子，走调了
Young man, that piano is out of tune.
拜托别弹了
Please don't.
小伙子
Young man.
别弹！
Stop!
那首曲
That song.
不是我的最爱
Not one of my favorites.
停下来！
Stop!
拿来看看
Let's have a look.
快跑！
Get out!
你好，多萝西夫人
Hey, Madame Dorothea.
有看见克拉蕾吗？
Have you seen Clary?
我刚收到短信说她在这儿
I just got a text that said she was here.
没有
No.
好吧，我只是…
Okay. Well, I'll just...
西蒙！
Simon!
西蒙，这不是真的她！
Simon, it's not really her!
西蒙！
Simon!
我来照顾他
I'll take care of him.
西蒙！
Simon!
她拿走了圣杯！
She's got the Cup!
西蒙！
Simon!
对不起
I'm sorry.
杰斯！
Jace!
图符不起作用
The runes aren't working.
西蒙，跟着我
Simon, you follow me.
把他们切碎
You cut these up.
不要 够了
Don't. You've done enough.
别这样对她 这不是她的错
Don't talk to her like that. This isn't her fault.
- 不，你说的对，是你的错  - 伊莎贝尔！
- No, you're right. This is your fault. - Isabelle!
亚力克一直都告诫你你会受伤
Alec kept telling you that you were going to get hurt.
你会让我们都受伤
You were going to get us all hurt.
现在他却快死了
Now he's the one dying.
我们需要找到圣杯
Well, we needed to get the Mortal Cup.
但还有别的办法
But there were other ways to do it
没必要为此伤害你的挚友
than getting your best friend killed.
去找霍奇
Why don't you go get Hodge.
我从没想让亚力克这样
I never wanted anything to happen to Alec.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们同意一起做的，我们一个团队
We agreed to do this together. We're a team.
有了克拉蕾，我们就不是一个团队了
Since Clary got here, we haven't been a team.
霍奇
Hodge!
亚力克受伤了
Alec's getting worse.
我知道
I know.
我已经叫人来了
I've already sent for someone.
你得到圣杯了吗？
Did you get the Cup?
然后呢？
What now?
霍奇？
Hodge?
你根本不知道
You have no idea what it's like
克拉夫的诅咒是什么滋味
living with the Clave's curse,
不能从这儿踏出一步
unable to set so much as a foot outside,
连开窗户都害怕
afraid to even open a window.
克拉蕾，别太怪我
Try not to judge me too harshly, Clary.
霍奇，你要做什么？
Hodge, what have you done?
我知道你终将把圣杯给我
I always knew you would bring me the Cup.
只是时间问题而已
It was only a matter of time.
我妈妈在哪儿？
Where is she?
她很好
She's fine.
你得到了想要的，现在放她走
You got what you want. Now let her go.
我得看看这是不是真的
I have to make sure you gave me the real one.
每个人为了圣杯都会不择手段
Everybody wants the Cup for the wrong reason.
那你没有吗？
And you don't?
拥有它
With this Cup,
我才能净化我的血统
I can cleanse our bloodlines,
拯救我们的种族
Save our race.
你也许不太了解人类历史
You might not know much about mundane history,
听着，当人们谈论保护种族时
but I can tell you when people start talking about preserving a race,
从没好事发生
it never goes well.
这就是为何我妈妈要用一生时间隐瞒你
That's why my mom spent her whole life hiding it from you.
不
No.
她不是要藏圣杯
She wasn't hiding the Cup.
她是要藏着你
She was hiding you.
喝下去
Drink.
我不会喝的
I'm not gonna drink that.
你为什么这么害怕？
Why are you so afraid?
你还没出生就已经喝过它了
You've been drinking this since before you were born.
我在你妈妈怀孕时就给她喝过
I fed it to your mother while you were in her womb.
快点，克拉蕾
Come on, Clary.
你现在应该猜到
You must have guessed by now.
你所有神奇的天赋
All these amazing talents
都是你母亲一直想要压制的
that your mother so desperately tried to suppress,
你觉得它从何而来？
where do you think they came from?
你是我女儿
You're my daughter.
我的血液流淌在你的身上
My blood runs in your veins.
现在…
Now...
喝
Drink.
快喝！
Drink!
把它拿出来！
Take that out!
不！
No!
有人进入穿梭门了
Someone just went through the Portal.
我去看看
I'll go check.
抱歉
Sorry.
我有点太激动了
I got a bit carried away.
卢克，你是…
Luke, you're a...
克拉蕾，听我说，听着 别害怕
Clary, listen to me, listen. Don't be afraid.
- 听着，好吗？  - 别碰我！
- Listen, right? - Don't touch me!
嘿，别这样
Hey, there's no need for that.
那东西还会回来
That thing will be back.
这儿不安全
We are not safe out here.
我跳进穿梭门，为了躲瓦伦丁
I jumped through the Portal to get away from Valentine.
我以为会到我妈妈那儿
I thought I'd end up with my mom.
但是我却到了最不想来的地方
Instead, I ended up in the last place I wanted to be.
听着，穿梭门带你来
Listen, the Portal brought you here
说明你一定想到我了
because you must have been thinking of me.
你内心深处仍信任我
Deep inside, you know you can trust me.
你说过一点都不在乎
You said you couldn't care
我们发生什么事情
less what happened to either of us.
你跟别人一样，只是想要圣杯
You just want the Cup, like everyone else.
我说过要保护你，我还能怎么做？
I said that to protect you. What else could I do?
这次我得一直照看你
Been keeping an eye on you this whole time.
在旅店那儿的是你
That was you at the hotel.
话说投的好啊
Good throw, by the way.
我怎么办？
What about me?
你怎么办？
What about you?
我们说好的
We had a deal.
我仍然没得到圣杯，不是吗？
Well, I still don't have my Cup, do I?
我一直信守诺言
I held up my end of the bargain.
不，你没有
No, you didn't.
我把圣杯给你了
I gave you the Cup.
是你给克拉蕾的 不是我的错
You handed it to Clary. That's not my fault.
帮我解咒
Now lift it.
听着，这都是你脑子想的
Listen, it's all in your head.
不，不！
No. No!
有诅咒
There's a spell.
真的？诅咒？
Really? A spell?
这只是问题的借口
That's just an excuse for a real problem
在这儿
in there.
你以为我真的可以解决吗？
Do you really think I can fix that?
我给你圣杯了，你帮我带走恐惧
I give you the Cup, you take away the fear.
没有圣杯我也一样寸步难行
Without the Cup, I'm as stuck as you are.
我的恐惧才是真的
Except my fear is real.
每个地下生物
Every Downworlder,
每个守护者
every member of the Clave,
每个暗影猎人都在穿梭门另一侧
every Shadowhunter on both sides of the Portal
找我
is looking for me right now.
我才需要一切帮助
I'm going to need all the help I can get.
瓦伦丁，你不必这样的
You don't have to go through with this, Valentine.
邪灵从来没到过神院
A demon has never set foot in the Institute.
现在是时候让他们来了
Well, maybe it's time they did.
我等这等好多年了
I've been waiting all these years to do this.
我别无选择
Clary's given me no choice.
她会回来的
She'll come back.
真的吗？
Really?
你敢确定？
And what makes you so sure?
这儿有她需要的人，像她需要她妈妈一样
There's someone here she wants as much as her mother.
你可以骗他们
If you lie and tell them
说他们都是你的孩子
they're both your children,
你这样就能让他们心碎
you'll break their hearts.
那又怎么样？
What can I say?
心碎的人最听话
The broken make the best followers.
看看你
Look at you.
爱就是灭亡
To love is to destroy.
霍奇到底在哪里？
Where the hell is Hodge?
我们没多少时间了
We don't have much time.
- 这弄对了吗？  - 不
- Does this look right to you? - No.
快看
Hey, look.
马格努斯？
Magnus?
我需要这些，要很多
I'm going to need all of this. Lots of it.
拿着
Take this.
封锁此地
Lock this place down.
杀死一切异族
Those who are not allies must be killed.
别动 它们
Don't do that!
瓦伦丁
Valentine.
乔纳森
Jonathan.
你怎么知道我的真名？
How do you know my real name?
没人这样叫过我
Nobody calls me that.
是真的吗？
Is it true?
瓦伦丁是我父亲？
Is Valentine my father?
他曾是个好人
You know, he was a great man,
在和守护者冲突之前
until his conflict with the Clave.
但你妈妈偷走圣杯后
But when your mother ran away with the Cup,
他害怕遭守护者惩罚
he was just so afraid of retribution from the Clave,
他烧毁了住处
he burned their house down to the ground.
他要世人相信他死了
He wanted the world to believe he was dead.
我们在灰烬里找到一个男人
In the ashes, we found the remains of a man
和小孩
and a child.
等等，一个小孩？
Wait a second, there was a child?
瓦伦丁怒火中烧
Valentine was so enraged, he wanted her to believe
他想要她相信他和他儿子都死了
he killed himself and their son,
你的哥哥
your brother.
我有个哥哥？
I have a brother?
乔纳森·克里斯托弗·摩根斯坦
Jonathan Christopher Morgenstern.
你撒谎
You're lying.
我姓名是杰斯·维兰德
My name is Jace Wayland.
我是维兰德家族的
And my family are the Waylands.
你以为只有克拉蕾被封存了记忆吗？
You think Clary is the only one with a block in her mind?
让你看看什么是真相
Let me show you the truth.
你没有驯服它，你毁了它
You didn't tame him. You broke him.
不！你…
No! You...
你不是我父亲
You are not my father.
我来是要让你知道自己到底是谁
I came back to help you understand who you really are.
我懂你在这不开心
I know you're unhappy here.
要守很多规矩
Plagued by rules.
你的名字辈分仅次于我
Your place is next to me.
你是摩根斯坦家族一员
You're a Morgenstern.
你是我儿子
And you're my son.
我叫杰斯·维兰德
My name is Jace Wayland.
我是维兰德家族的
I'm a Wayland.
抱歉告诉你这个消息
Sorry to break this to you,
但也是时候该知道了
but it's time you heard the truth.
不
Don't.
只是理解方式的问题
It's all a matter of perception.
看到了吗？摩根斯坦
You see, Morgenstern.
- 拿着  - 好
- Take this. - Okay.
好
Okay.
伊莎贝尔
Isabelle.
克拉蕾？
Clary?
我们找到你妈妈了
Yeah, we found your mom.
他们找到她了
They found her.
在神院
She's at the Institute.
阿拉里克
Alaric.
我是卢克，你看到了吗？
It's Luke. Can you see it?
是的，我看到了
Yeah, I see it.
兄弟们，得走了
Hey, guys, we have to go.
卢克需要咱们
Luke needs us.
我们去哪？
Where are we headed?
神院
The Institute.
我们这是在破坏协议
We'd be breaking the accords.
不变身就没关系
Not if we stay human.
走，兄弟们！
Let's go, guys!
快走，快走！
Go, go, go, go!
快，动起来！
Come on, move it!
准备就绪！
Ready to go!
一切听指挥
They've all been briefed.
他是阿拉里克，我们的人
This is Alaric. He's one of us.
走吧
Go ahead.
如果需要可以将头伸出窗外
You can hang your head out the window if you need to.
我是狼人
I'm a werewolf
不是金毛犬
not a golden retriever.
西蒙！
Simon!
在这等，我会回来
Just wait here, I'll be back.
啥？不 伊莎贝尔，我不能…
What? No. Isabelle, I can't just...
不，伊莎贝尔！
No. Isabelle!
回来，伊莎贝尔，你去哪？
Come on, Isabelle, where are you?
好，上！
All right, move it!
快点，上！
Come on, move it!
好吧
All right.
狼人来救我们了
The werewolves are here to save us.
难以置信我这么说
Never thought I'd say that.
伊莎贝尔
Finally! Isabelle.
打开
Hey, open up the door.
起作用了
It looks like he's responding.
他能挺过来
He'll survive.
小心
And be careful.
有人入侵
You're being invaded.
召集所有邪灵…
Summoning all these bloody demons...
跑！
Run!
快跑！
- 走哪里？  - 那有另一个出口！
- Where are we going? - There's another exit!
等等
Wait.
伊莎贝尔！
Isabelle!
- 我差点杀死你了  - 是啊
- I almost killed you. - Yeah.
你还好吗？
You okay?
- 没事，我没事  - 来吧
- Yeah, yeah. I'm fine. - Come on.
这破地方全是邪灵
This place is full of demons.
这不可能
That's impossible.
神院是圣地
The Institute is hallowed ground.
他们还不知情
Yeah, no one seems to have told them that.
肯定有内鬼放他们进来
Someone on the inside must have let them in.
原是救援行动
This is a rescue mission.
我们可没装备作战
We are not equipped to fight demons.
- 分开！  - 这边！这边！
- Spread out! - That way! That way!
后退！快！
Move back! Come on!
阿拉里克，我们需要支援！
We could use some help here, Alaric!
阿拉里克！
Alaric!
振作点，这肯定还有别的出入，是吧？
Come on, there must be some other way out of here, right?
不，这里没有，西蒙！
No, there isn't, Simon!
我们撑不了多久！
We can't hold them much longer!
让开
Step away.
让开！
Step away!
克拉蕾，这是什么图符？
Clary, which rune is that?
我也不知道，它是…
I don't know, it's just...
- 我从没见过  - 真的吗？
- I've never seen it before. - Really?
不在书上
It's not in the book.
它在消退
It's fading.
肯定有地方放他们进来
Here, they're coming in through somewhere.
我得去阻止他们
I'm going to stop them.
快点
Come on.
你们现走
You guys go.
我们垫后
We'll catch up.
不！
No!
他们从屋顶下来的，跟上
They're coming from the dome. Come on.
乔丝琳
Jocelyn,
我一直惦记你
you never left my heart.
我现在带你回家
I've come to take you home.
她哪儿也不去
She's not going anywhere.
你怎么上来的
How did you get up here?
你比我想象的更强大
You're even more powerful than I anticipated.
离她远点
Get away from her.
干嘛？
What the hell?
听他说
Just listen to what he has to say.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
终于…
Finally...
我的两个孩子团聚了
Both my children together.
我女儿
My daughter
和我儿子
and my son.
对不起，克拉蕾
I'm so sorry, Clary.
我原先不知道
I didn't know.
瓦伦丁在撒谎
Valentine's lying.
你是迈克尔·维兰德的儿子
You're Michael Wayland's son.
卢克说我哥哥已经死了
Luke said my brother is dead.
他死于火灾
He died in a fire,
他们在灰烬里找到他遗骸
and they found his remains in the ashes.
我带乔纳森一起逃跑的
I took Jonathan with me when I ran.
那孩子遗骨是狼人所为
The bones were of a child killed by wolves.
但愿这不是真的
I wish it wasn't true.
她不愿意相信
She doesn't want to believe you
因为她爱上你了，乔纳森
because she is in love with you, Jonathan.
我以为你叫杰斯
I thought your name was Jace.
杰斯是小名
Jace is a nickname.
乔纳森·克里斯托弗…
Jonathan Christopher...
J.C.
杰斯
Jace.
把手在这
There's the lever.
你进去，我阻止他们
You go close the dome and I'll hold them off.
把圣杯拿出来，克拉蕾
Take out the Cup, Clary.
拿出圣杯！
Take out my Cup!
我要你拿！
I want that Cup!
你说过不伤害她！
You said you wouldn't hurt her!
够了！
Enough!
说够了
That's enough.
现在！
Now!
卡住了！
It's stuck!
关掉它！
Close it!
不行！
I can't!
好像少了一块！
I think there's a piece missing!
克拉蕾！
Clary!
我非常需要它
I really need this.
妈妈？
Mom?
- 去找其他人  - 好
- Find the others. - All right.
好吧，你是要上还是下呢？
All right, you want to take the upstairs or the down?
我对底下不感冒
I'm not too crazy about the basement.
我撑不了太久！
I can't hold them back any longer!
西蒙，快点！
Simon, hurry!
克拉蕾！
Clary!
嗨，卢克先生
Hello, Mr. Garroway.
看起来今天你很悲剧，嗯？
Looks like you're having a rough day, eh?
我觉得这种情况下直接杀了你
I guess the humane thing to do in this situation
会仁慈点
would be to put you down.
你想看我变身吗？
But you wanted to see me change.
是的
I do.
起来！
Get up!
那么，你到底要反抗到什么时候？
So, boy, how far do you want to take this?
到死为止
To the end.
西蒙！
Simon!
伊莎贝尔！
Isabelle!
靠着我
Lean on me.
出去！快！
Get out! Go on!
离开这儿
Get out of here.
快跑！
Come on!
走！
Go!
听说你喜欢弹琴
Somebody told me that you like to play music.
歌德会为此骄傲的
Johann would be very proud.
你该死在拉齐尔剑下
Now you shall die by Raziel's sword.
住手！
Stop!
要么我就丢了它！
Or I'll drop it!
你不会那么做的
You don't want to do that.
克拉蕾，别给他
Don't give it to him, Clary.
你先听我说
I need you to listen to me.
我是你爸爸
As your father,
我求你了
I'm begging you.
要是我爸爸就一定懂我
If you'd been a real dad,
懂得圣杯在哪里
you'd know me well enough to imagine where the Cup is,
知道我心底想的地方
where my deepest thoughts are taking it.
你一点都不懂我
You don't know the first thing about me.
你不是我爸…
You're not my dad...
永远不是
And you never will be.
我保证你不会再见到我
I promise, you'll never have to see me again.
克拉蕾，谢谢
Thank you, Clary.
没有圣杯，我们会输的
Without this Cup, we are lost.
不是“我们”
Not "we."
是你
You.
克拉蕾！
Clary!
- 不！抓住我！  - 决不！
- No! Don't let go! - Never!
这儿！
Here!
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道你之前为什么那样做了
I understand why you did what you did.
我原谅你
And I forgive you.
我要你知道
I want you to know,
我会为你保密
your secret's safe with me.
她怎么样了？
So, how's she doing?
情况稳定了
Stable.
医生不知道她喝过什么
The doctors don't know what she took,
只能等
so we just have to wait.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我觉得我只是一个老古董
I guess I'm an old romantic.
我总希望当我向某人说
I always hoped that when I finally said
“我爱你”时，她会说同样的话
"I love you" to someone, she'd say the same thing back.
那个人会的
And that someone will.
但愿吧
Yeah, I know.
你很累了
Hey, you're tired.
去休息吧，我们会照看好她
Go sleep, we'll take care of her.
好，抱一个
Yeah, come on.
我喜欢你收拾这里
I like what you've done with the place.
我只是耍了些把戏
I've got a few tricks up my sleeve.
克拉蕾，我们真怕你不会回来了
Clary, we're afraid you're not coming back.
只是现在跟你作伴真的很难
It's just really hard to be around you right now.
对我来说也一样
It's hard for me as well.
但是这不仅仅是我们
But this is about more than us.
你有不可思议的天赋，我们需要你
You have an incredible gift, and we need you.
我需要你
I need you.
我不知道
I just don't know.
还记得我说过从没见过天使？
Remember when I said I'd never seen an angel?
我撒谎了
Well, I lied.
你是我见过最勇敢的凡人
You're still the bravest mundane I've ever met.
我可不是凡人
I'm not a mundane.
等等，杰斯！
Wait, Jace!
慢慢来啊
You took your time.
你说过你需要我
You said you needed me.
你该好好保存它
You should keep that safe.
我会的
Yeah.
我可以抱着你吗…
Is it okay if I...
我能…
Do I...
- 这样可以吗…  - 没关系
- Is it okay if I... - Yeah.
听着，克拉蕾，我不相信它
Look, Clary, I don't believe it.
这似乎不是真的，不在我的心里
It doesn't feel like the truth, not in my heart.
我只是不懂如何去面对这个世界
I just don't know how to look at the world anymore.
我看不到街道，红绿灯和车
I don't see streets and traffic lights and cars.
眼前只是邪灵和天使
I see demons and angels.
一切都变了
Everything's different.
世界还是一样的
The world's the same.
你才是变了的那个
You're the one who's different.
你还记得霍奇说的吗？
Don't you remember what Hodge said?
什么？
What?
所以故事都是真的
All the stories are true.
感谢观影